RG 135, The Union Company, Hartford, Connecticut
Connecticut State Library
Union Company records
1801-1862
Connecticut State Library
Union Company (Hartford, Conn.)
1.25 cubic feet
The Union Company was incorporated in 1800 to clear a channel in the Connecticut River from Hartford to Long Island Sound. After the channel was cleared, the Company was allowed to collect tolls from vessels using the river.
RG135
1914-001
Historical Note
The Union Company was incorporated in 1800 to clear a channel in the Connecticut River from Hartford to Long Island Sound. After the channel was cleared, the Company was allowed to collect tolls from vessels using the river.
Scope and Content
Included are records of directors’ meetings, accounts, financial records, checkbook stubs, stock book ledgers, and receipt books.
Related Material
RG 001, Early General Records, Trade and Maritime Affairs, especially 2nd Series, Vol. 1, 12-43.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Union Company (Hartford, Conn.)
Places:
Hartford (Conn.)
Subjects:
Union Company (Hartford, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut River -- Navigation; Inland water transportation -- Transit charges -- Connecticut; Tolls -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Receipts (financial records); Checkbooks; Correspondence; Journals (accounts); Ledgers (account books); Minutes
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provence
Accessioned by the Connecticut State Library on May 19, 1944. The records were transferred from RG 069 on December 4, 1975.
Container List
- Records, 1801-1862
  - 1. Directors meetings minute book, 1811-1862 (Volume 1)
  - 2. Journal, 1801-1849 (Volume 2)
  - 3. Ledgers, 1801-1849
    - 1801-1824 (Volume 3)
      Separate index inside front cover.
    - 1801-1849 (Volume 4)
  - 4. Copy of accounts exhibited to Hartford County Court and to the General Assembly, 1807-1827 (Volume 5)
  - 5. Check book stubs, 1841-1848, 1853-1861
    - 1841 August 25 - 1844 April 30 (Volume 6)
    - 1844 May 27 - 1848 March 4 (Volume 7)
    - 1853 June 3 - 1861 (Volume 8)
  - 6. Stock book journal, 1801-1828 (Volume 9)
  - 7. Stock book ledger, 1801-1828 (Volume 10)
  - 8. Stock receipt stub books, 1801-1818
    - 1801-1810 (Volume 11)
    - 1810-1818 (Volume 12)
  - 9. Miscellaneous financial records, 1801-1822; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - List of notes due, undated (Folder 13)
    - Blank checks from Hartford Trust Co. (Folder 13)
    - Record of account, anonymous, 1807-1822 (Folder 13)
    - Estimate on funds of the Union Company and periods of payment, 1801-1822 (Folder 13)
    - Check books, 1813-1815; 2 items (Folder 13)
      One check book is blank.